Nicole: Ethical conduct refers to
standards of behaviour that are
appropriate and shows understanding
of what is right and what is wrong.
Abraham: In cyber security unlike
other industries there is no specific
code of ethics though many employers
and organisations will have their own
codes of conduct or ethics covering
other aspects of their organisations,
as well as security that need to
be complied with by all staff.
Nicole: It is also very important that
all organisations that handle data do
so in an ethical way to make sure that
they abide by legislation and regulations
that we have already looked at relating
to the use of computers and data.
Abraham: All organisations and
companies will have an IT policy
in place, and some will also have
a specific cyber security policy.
These will be regularly reviewed
and updated to keep in touch with
ever changing laws and regulations.
Nicole: Most new employees must sign
up to a policy agreement as part
of their induction to say that they
will follow all guidelines including
ethical ones especially where specific
sensitive data is concerned and
GDPR rules need to be adhered to.
There are a range of ethical rules that
link to legislation when it comes to
using computer systems that apply such as:
• Abraham: Not using computer
equipment to harm others.
• Not interfering with
other’s computers and work
• Not looking through other’s
files without their permission.
• Not using a computer to
steal or cause mischief.
• Not copying software.
• Not using other people’s
resources without permission.
• Acting without regard for consequences.
• And having respect for data security.
Nicole: With remote working, more
employees work from home, but, all
of these rules should still apply.
And remember ethical conduct goes
both ways employees may sync their
work emails to their smartphones, and
employers may come to expect workers
to check emails outside office hours.
Abraham: It is not ethical of a business
to expect employees to be available at all
hours unless this is part of their role.